<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Misc on Dang-Khoa&#39;s blog </title>
    <link>http://dangkhoasdc.github.io/tags/misc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Misc on Dang-Khoa&#39;s blog </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Dang-Khoa</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://dangkhoasdc.github.io/tags/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Miscellaneous notes</title>
      <link>http://dangkhoasdc.github.io/post/why_so_serious/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dangkhoasdc.github.io/post/why_so_serious/</guid>
      <description>Therer are some not-so-serious miscellaneous thoughts, comments of mine about everything in an informal format using Vietnamese and English.
Table of Contents  Deep Learning and truely science researching &amp;ldquo;Thời gian trôi như chó chạy ngoài đồng&amp;rdquo; How to classify images of fruit Chuyện fake news, fake quotes và toxic information.  References    Deep Learning and truely science researching    &amp;ldquo;too often where people will something against their own gut instincts because they think the community wants them to do it that way, so people will work on a certain subject even though they aren&amp;rsquo;t terribly interested in it because they think that they&amp;rsquo;ll get more prestige by working on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Ubuntu on Windows?</title>
      <link>http://dangkhoasdc.github.io/post/ubuntu_on_windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dangkhoasdc.github.io/post/ubuntu_on_windows/</guid>
      <description>For programming purposes, I prefer Linux to Windows. However, Windows is really good at entertaining and office works. Beside, Microsoft Office is the best office suit I ever have experienced, and OneNote is one of my favorite note-taking software. Not to mention my beloved Bilizzard games such as Diablo, Starcraft and other video games.
A solution to integrate Windows and Linux in one machine is to install dual-boot. However, I am tired of switching between 2 OSs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>